# **Bassem Marji**

Project Implementation Manager



### **Personal Information**



St. 215, Chiyah, Beirut, LB.



+961 70 672199



bassemmarji@gmail.com



12/01/1978



linkedin.com/in/bassem-marji-0280611b5



https://github.com/bassemmarji

## Languages



### **Technical & Soft Skills**

Oracle & PL-SQL Ms. SQL MySQL Python Java Shell Scripting



## Leadership

Emotional Intelligence

Resilience

Result driven

Communication

Adaptability

### **Certificates**



Oracle certified Associate (12c)

## Summary



Energetic, driven and accomplished Project Implementation Manager with 18+ years of experience holding a Master degree in Management Information System (MIS).

Spearheaded the implementation of over 50 projects and propelled the digital transformation of mission critical applications.

A highly versatile IT professional with technical skills and competencies in conceptualizing and supporting multi-faceted IT frameworks, forging vendor relationship and devising strategies that solve business problems.

## Work experience

## Senior Systems Integration Specialist

2005 to Present



**BLOM Bank**, Lebanon

- Manage projects end to end from cradle to grave.
- Partner with technology delivery managers for technical implementation projects using Agile, Waterfall or Hybrid delivery methods.
- Coordinate and validate the change management process.
- Design and build API management solutions.
- > Streamline the vendor relationship and craft strategies for new software acquisitions.

#### Portfolio of key projects:



Moody's Riskanalyst (2 M\$) FIS Asset Liability Management (1 M\$)

Wolters Kluwer OneSumX (1 M\$)

#### Software Engineer

2000-2005

1996 - 2002



### MEDCO Petroleum Company, Lebanon

- Drove all phases of a microprocessor smart card project to a successful completion (C++ and Oracle).
- Designed, developed and installed dozens of modules using Oracle PLS-QL ranging from stock management, billing to HR which earned the highest customer satisfaction.

#### Software Developer

2003-2005 Part time

#### 3DS, Lebanon

Collaborated with peers on redesigning and improving numerous applications targeting various business lines.

## **Education**

Master in Management Information System (MIS)
Saint Joseph University of Beirut (USJ/IGE)

Bachelor's degree in Demography
Lebanese University (LU)

## **Courses**

	PMI-PMP Project Manag	ement Professional	03-2018
₩.			

PMI-RMP Risk Management Professional
GEMPLUS MPCOS-EMV Smart card programming
09-2000